## Joel Milligan | Software Engineer

Amsterdam

Engineer with Frontend and Backend development experience focused on writing clean, easily-readible, and tested code. Passionate about the environment, green energy, and technology, currently obtaining my Master's in Green Software. Up to 3 references upon request.

## Relevant Work Experience

## **GUTS Tickets/Get Protocol**

Amsterdam, NL

2022-Present

Working on backend Golang (fasthttp) and Python (Django/Flask) webservices together with RabbitMQ and PostgresSQL database. Also working on a React Native app and was able to improve the check-in experience for users at events by reducing failing codes within the app by 10%.

USAA San Antonio, TX - Remote

Full-Stack Engineer

Backend Engineer

2020-2022

Worked with NodeJS (Express) and Python (Django/Flask) backend webapplications for Slack and Box integrations. Helped to onboard USAA by migrating their 65,000 employees from Skype onto Slack.

Datasite

Platform (Backend) Engineer

2018-2020

Worked on NodeJS microservices, some of which used GraphQL along with RMQ and Mongo. Designed and coordinated the team through a Database schema redesign and migration that reduced load times from over 9000 miliseconds to under 1500 miliseconds for the most important queries.

Universal Studios Orlando, FL

Microservices Engineer

2018

Worked in NodeJS microservices (Express). Later was placed as lead of a 5-person team with the goal of rewriting several microservices at the park to be eventually consistent instead of strongly consistent.

• Additional history available on request.

## **Education**

VU/UvA Joint Master's Degree in Software Engineering and Green IT
Networked Systems Performance, Distributed Algorithms, Adaptive Software, ML/AI
2022—Present

**Technical Proficiencies** 

- **Programming Languages:** Golang, NodeJS/Typescript, Python.
- Tools and Frameworks: Git, Gitflow, Gitlab/Github CI, Kubernetes, PostgresSQL, MongoDB, Docker, NPM/Yarn, React, React Native.
- Interpersonal: Communication within and across teams, comfortable presenter, proactive.